Finding Aid for George J. Huebner papers, 1954-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
George J. Huebner papers 1954-1976
Huebner, George J., 1910-
1 linear foot
85211 Aa 2
Chief of engineering research at the Chrysler Corporation; correspondence, speeches, articles by and about him, photographs, and miscellanea.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of George Huebner (donor no. 6488 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
George J. Huebner was chief of engineering research at the Chrysler Corporation. At Chrysler, Huebner was an advocate of gas turbine engine research.
The Huebner collection consists of a single series of speeches, articles, and biographical materials. Also included are three folders of photographs which include photographs of Huebner and his wife Gertrude Huebner; photographs of Huebner with automobiles having gas turbine engines; and photographs of Huebner with other automotive executives and engineers. One of the photos is of Wernher Von Braun.
Subjects:
Automobile industry and trade--United States.; Chrysler Corporation.; Engineering.; Engineers--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Automobile industry.; Chrysler Corporation.; Engines.; Huebner, Gertrude, 1915-; Huebner, George J., 1910-; Von Braun, Wernher, 1912-1977.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Speeches, articles, biographical material
  - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Material for Elmer A. Sperry Award, 1963-1968 (Box 1)
  - Nomination and forms to National Academy of Engineers, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Biographical material, list of published articles, and activities (Box 1)
  - Published articles (by and about Huebner), 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Clippings file, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Speeches
    - 1954 (Box 1)
    - 1956 (Box 1)
    - 1958 (Box 1)
    - 1959 (Box 1)
    - 1960 (Box 1)
    - 1961 (Box 1)
    - 1962 (Box 1)
    - 1963 (Box 1)
    - 1964 (Box 1)
    - 1965 (Box 1)
    - 1967 (Box 1)
    - 1968 (Box 1)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - 1975 (Box 1)
    - Undated (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 3 envelopes (Box 1)